Ken Eucker



EMAIL keneucker@gmail.com

LINKS

http://keneucker.com, https://www.linkedin.com/in/keneucker/, https://github.com/keneucker

Profile

I am a full stack web developer, classically trained in object oriented programming, who likes to write universal javascript, with extensive experience building the backend of web connected properties. I have a diverse set of skills writing in the serverside languages C#, PHP, Javascript, and the clientside languages HTML, Javascript, CSS, JSX, including the database languages mysql, MSSQL, and Mongodb.

I seek to help others with their relationship with technology through software solutions both web and native.

Employment History

Feb 2017 - Dec 2018 PORTLAND

Web Developer

Digital Trends

Full Stack Web Developer working in PHP, Node, HTML, and Javascript on a Wordpress platform that serves content to over 5,000 concurrent users a day. In my primary role as a shared resource for another department in the organization, I develop solutions and maintain integrations for all of the needs of that department including automating processes. Daily participant in standup meetings, software project planning meetings, and system architecture meetings. As a self starting leader on a team of leaders, I interface with stakeholders and other team members to continuously iterate on solutions that have a direct impact on our digital publication businesses.

During my time at Digital Trends I developed a new ESP integration from the ground up using test-driven development methodologies, refactored newsletter emails and the code that runs the signup modules on the site, implemented a couple of linking features on our articles, and implemented a new article type with a slideshow; all for the WordPress platform of digitaltrends.com.

My greatest work at Digital Trends is an end to end solution for encapsulating our adcode with site-specific integration code and business logic which is deployed to AWS S3, Lambda, and Api Gateway. A project that started as a skunkworks solution for my own process which I whole heartedly developed into a fully featured build automation tool.

I also upped my foosball game.

Jun 2011 – Jan 2017 PORTLAND

Freelance Software Engineer

Seven Twenty Studios LLC

Custom software development and systems architecture engineer for web connected technologies in both the business and personal sectors. I collaborate on small teams with diversely separate sets of skills to deliver websites. Project technologies include a focus on PHP, HTML, and MySql with equal experience in C# and ASP.NET and MSSQL. I enjoy projects that enable efficient client facing changes as well as automating underlying architecture decisions.

In 2014 I began contracting full time as a remote employee. I continue to work on small teams as a collaborative developer as well as consulting with interactive producers to provide long term architectural designs that benefit the business needs that clients are looking for. I enjoy developing code using github as an all-encompassing development solution and delivering solutions from design to version 2 iterations and anywhere in between.

Mar 2016 - Dec 2016 PORTLAND

Web Developer

Solid Interactive

At Solid; I was involved in client meetings, standups, development planning sessions, and company wide tactic meetings as a web developer.

I am an active polyglot at Solid and I include myself on projects for the web using the Microsoft stack, PHP and Mysql stack, as well as pure HTML and Javascript website projects. I interface with project managers and clients to provide new features and implementations to existing sites as well as maintenance and issues that arise.

I participate with other developers on the team in sprint planning, story and defect weighting, and tech roundtables about new and exciting technologies.

Mar 2014 – Apr 2015 PORTLAND

Contract Web Developer

R/West

Backend web services developer and software architecture designer focusing on projects in php, mysql, javascript, and html. Developed concurrently on version one and version two implementations that saw growth and reached scalability. Agile methodologies and version control using github while working directly with server environments for deployment.

Dec 2011 - Jan 2014 PORTLAND

Software Development Engineer

Viewpoint Construction Software

Developer role in scrum process on systems team: attended daily scrums, participated in weighting sprints, defect ticket management. Coordinated development efforts with Project Manager, Support, and Quality

Assurance teams.

Core development in ASP.NET C#, Multi-Tier SQL, VB.NET Winforms on flagship Viewpoint Construction Software.

May 2010 - Jul 2011 PORTLAND

Software Developer 1

Overland Agency

Team developer and scrum participant. Worked mostly in bug fixing, qa testing, and technical design contributor of a proprietary CMS offering customizations for various clients. Worked within ASP.NET and MSSQL for both client and server side enhancements to existing projects.

Lead Silverlight development for all projects: "Fresh Local Music" Delivered a Silverlight out of browser music app that runs on laptops in the store locations and updates external database.

Education

Sep 2006 - Jun 2010 KLAMATH FALLS

Oregon Institute of Technology

Bachelor's of Science in Computer Software Engineering Technology

Skills

Software Architecture Design ● ● ● C# ASP.NET ● ● ● ● Javascript HTML • • • CSS Mysql ● ● ● ■ NodeJs MSSQL ● ● ● ● AWS services (Lambda, S3, •••• Cloudfront)

References

References available upon request